<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Hutson</title>
    <link>http://adamhutson.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Hutson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamhutson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloning Cassandra Clusters The Fast Way</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cloning-cassandra-clusters-the-fast-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cloning-cassandra-clusters-the-fast-way/</guid>
      <description>Cloning Cassandra clusters is not something that is talked about in the community a whole lot. Do a quick google search on “Clone Cassandra” and there aren’t many hits. Mostly just the DataStax docs and a few StackOverflow questions. Albeit, it’s just a practice in backup and restore, but it’s still a valid edge use case. The good news is, if you’re taking backups, you’re halfway there. This post will walk you through the steps to clone your cassandra data the fast way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing Cassandra Data</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/sizing-cassandra-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/sizing-cassandra-data/</guid>
      <description>Size does matter. One of the basic tasks of a Data Modeler is to know how big your data is going to get. You need to provide estimates of how much disk your model will consume.
 How fast is it coming? Another basic task is to know how fast your data is flowing inbound. Figuring out how quickly, or slowly, it will grow is important for capacity planning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Physical Data Modeling</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-physical-data-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-physical-data-modeling/</guid>
      <description>The task of a data modeler is to create order out of chaos without excessively distorting the truth. The finished product should be a data model that describes the structure, manipulation and integrity aspects of the data to be stored. To properly create a data model, the modeler will transform said chaos through three distinct stages. The first is a Conceptual Data Model, then a Logical Data Model, and lastly, a Physical Data Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Partitioning &amp; Clustering Keys Explained</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-partitioning-and-clustering-keys-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-partitioning-and-clustering-keys-explained/</guid>
      <description>Primary and Clustering Keys should be one of the very first things you learn about when modeling Cassandra data. Most people coming from a relational background automatically think, “Yeah, I know what a Primary Key is”, and gloss right over it. Because of this, there always seems to be a lot of confusion around the topic of Primary Keys in Cassandra. With this post, I will try to demystify the confusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Logical Data Modeling</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-logical-data-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-logical-data-modeling/</guid>
      <description>The task of a data modeler is to create order out of chaos without excessively distorting the truth. The finished product should be a data model that describes the structure, manipulation and integrity aspects of the data to be stored. To properly create a data model, the modeler will transform said chaos through three distinct stages. The first is a Conceptual Data Model, then a Logical Data Model, and lastly, a Physical Data Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of choosing Cassandra for your data</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/benefits-of-choosing-cassandra-for-your-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/benefits-of-choosing-cassandra-for-your-data/</guid>
      <description>Choosing the right tool for a project can sometimes be easy. For example, to drive a nail, the obvious choice would be a hammer. Other times, the choice is not as easy or obvious. A data engineer, like a good carpenter, needs to know that different tasks require different tools. Selecting which database will hold your data has many factors to consider before a decision is made.
 Apache Cassandra is one of the many tools that a data engineer should know how and when to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Conceptual Data Modeling</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-conceptual-data-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-conceptual-data-modeling/</guid>
      <description>The task of a data modeler is to create order out of chaos without excessively distorting the truth. The finished product should be a data model that describes the structure, manipulation and integrity aspects of the data to be stored. To properly create a data model, the modeler will transform said chaos through three distinct stages. The first is a Conceptual Data Model, then a Logical Data Model, and lastly, a Physical Data Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update your Cassandra data model for 3.0</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/update-your-cassandra-data-model-for-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/update-your-cassandra-data-model-for-30/</guid>
      <description>Apache Cassandra version 3.0 was released in September 2015. With the 3.0 release, some major updates to the storage engine and (long awaited) materialized views were introduced. For a Data Modeler, the addition of views are something to jump up and down about. However, over the last half year or so, many companies have been hesitant to make the jump from their trusted 2.1.x version. By the end of this post, I hope to help you understand:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Data Model Basics</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-data-model-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-data-model-basics/</guid>
      <description>Data. Model. What an odd combination of words. To someone outside of the world of I.T., it doesn’t make much sense. But to those people that have written software or attempted to store information, it’s a phrase all too often discussed. A data model, as defined by wiki, “is an abstract model that organizes elements of data and standardizes how they relate to one another and to properties of the real world”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring Cassandra Data</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/restoring-cassandra-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/restoring-cassandra-data/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve ever lost your production data or discovered that it had been corrupted, then you know the importance of being able to restore that data. Restoring your Cassandra data can be quick and painless. The following three methods will help you to gain a better understanding of what’s involved.
 Before you can begin to restore data though you have to have data to restore. You are backing up your data, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing Up Cassandra Data</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/backing-up-cassandra-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/backing-up-cassandra-data/</guid>
      <description>The Apache distribution of Cassandra does not automatically take backups of it’s data. However, it does include a tool to create backups. Backups in Cassandra are called “snapshots”. In the photography sense of the word, a snapshot is a picture of what the data looks like at a moment in time. Since data in Cassandra is immutable, taking a snapshot is quick, painless, and has very little impact on the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Create a Cassandra Cluster in AWS Part 2</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/how-to-create-a-cassandra-cluster-in-aws-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/how-to-create-a-cassandra-cluster-in-aws-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1 of this brief tutorial, I shared with you how to create a cluster in Amazon’s AWS. In Part 2, we’ll discuss installing and configuring cassandra on your new cluster.
   Log onto Virtual Machines Now that I have these three machines, how do I log onto them and start to use them.
 From the EC2 Dashboard, select the Instances tab on the left side. This will give you an overview of all the instances you have running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Create a Cassandra Cluster in AWS Part 1</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/how-to-create-a-cassandra-cluster-in-aws-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/how-to-create-a-cassandra-cluster-in-aws-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll walk you through creating a Cassandra cluster in Amazon’s Web Services. The first thing you’ll need to do is sign in to your Amazon Console. If you don’t have one, create an account. Once you’re logged in, from the dashboard, click on the EC2 logo, under the Compute section.
   This is Amazon’s Elastic Compute Cloud where you can launch virtual servers, known as an Amazon EC2 instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Summit 2015</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-summit-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/cassandra-summit-2015/</guid>
      <description>Imagine if you could create an event that was able to generate over a 4,000% increase in attendance over five years. Well, that’s exactly what DataStax has done with the annual Cassandra Summit in the Bay area.
 *4,000% increase in attendance*   This past week was the 2015 Cassandra Summit, held in Santa Clara, was the largest NoSQL conference in the world. Prior to the start, there were over 6,100 registrations onsite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Cassandra Instance In AWS EC2</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/simple-cassandra-instance-in-aws-ec2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/simple-cassandra-instance-in-aws-ec2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been doing Cassandra development in an enterprise setting for quite a while now. And being a good little development shop (Expedia), we had Chef set up to deploy stuff for us, including Cassandra installation. Chef is great at doing just that. The downside to that is that you forgot the details of how to install Cassandra manually. Here are the steps to spin up an EC2 instance and getting a single instance of Cassandra running on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Of The Rising Scrum</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/house-of-the-rising-scrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/house-of-the-rising-scrum/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I’m having fun with my blog titles twisting classic song titles. Get used to it, I think I’ll keep doing it.
 Fire Fighting After a couple of weeks at the new job, I noticed that there wasn’t really any direction to how issues were being addressed. It seemed like whatever the current fire was or whoever was pestering the loudest was getting their issue addressed first. This also meant that current issues being worked were being dropped for the latest “emergency” issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Times, They Are A Changing</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/the-times-they-are-a-changing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/the-times-they-are-a-changing/</guid>
      <description>Wow, it’s been almost three years since I blogged about anything here. I feel just a little bit bad about that, but honestly, it’s been a pretty busy time for me. My last post was about Alternatives to Relational Databases … yep, I’ve definitely been in that world for a while now. Back then, I was just starting to scratch the surface on what NoSQL even was. Looking at that post, now I realize I didn’t know nearly enough on the subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation On Alternatives To Relational Databases</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/presentation-on-alternatives-to-relational-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/presentation-on-alternatives-to-relational-databases/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, I’m presenting to a CISQ 250 class at Drury University. The topic of the presentation is “Alternatives to Relational Databases”.
 The following is my presentation in SlideShare.net:
 Alternatives to Relational Databases
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sql Presentation Fo Springfield .NET User&#39;s Group</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/sql-presentation-for-springfield-net-users-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/sql-presentation-for-springfield-net-users-group/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, I gave a presentation to the Springfield .NET Users Group. I chose to present on SQL Server 2008 Development for Programmers. I tried to keep it to a level 200 type class.
 The following is my presentation in SlideShare.net:
 SQL Server 2008 Development for Programmers
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCI Training Equals Lessons In How To Hack</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/pci-training-equals-lessons-in-how-to-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/pci-training-equals-lessons-in-how-to-hack/</guid>
      <description>Today at work, all developers were required to take an all-day training in PCI. This is the second such session that I’ve attended since I was hired. It’s all very interesting to learn about, however, it really boils down to hacking. They are teaching us all the methods that we (our websites) can be hacked. The surprising part is how much my co-workers already know about how to attack a site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Addition To The Family</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/new-addition-to-the-family/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/new-addition-to-the-family/</guid>
      <description>It’s been entirely too long since my last post. The last time I posted I had just started my new job and was blogging about the experience and silly setup reminders for myself. It’s been about 9 months and I am still loving Expedia! I have a great management team supporting me. And they like to have fun; the company held an off-site in Las Vegas, at the Palazzo for three days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Won A Pluralsight Subscription</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/won-a-pluralsight-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/won-a-pluralsight-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Tonight, at my local .NET User’s Group meeting, I was lucky enough to win a 1-year subscription to PluralSight On-Demand! The subscription was one of the give-aways that the group was doing. I am really fortunate to have won it, too. With my new job that focuses on Database side of development, I’ve been getting a little rusty at my coding skillset. The standard subscription lets me have full access to over 70 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is The Immediate Window In Visual Studio</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/where-is-the-immediate-window-in-visual-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/where-is-the-immediate-window-in-visual-studio/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I get a clean install of Visual Studio, I can never find the menu for displaying the Immediate Window for debugging code. The keyboard shortcut for it is: Ctl + Alt + I
 This post is probably more for my own reference later, but maybe it will satisfy someone’s search.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning A New Leaf With A Career Change</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/turning-a-new-leaf-with-a-career-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/turning-a-new-leaf-with-a-career-change/</guid>
      <description>I started a new job this week. I am working for Expedia, Inc now as a Database Development Engineer (or DB Dev, for short). So far, I am really enjoying the opportunity. The people are really great and have a real entusiasm for what they do.
 It’s a quicker pace for development releases than I’m used to, but it seems like they have a really good system of checks and balances to ensure the process is flawless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Many Todos And Not Enough Dones</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/too-many-todos-and-not-enough-dones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/too-many-todos-and-not-enough-dones/</guid>
      <description>I love taking on new projects, and I&amp;#8217;m a do-it-yourself kind of person. If there is something that needs to be done around the house, I don&amp;#8217;t hire it out, I do it myself. It&amp;#8217;s not just physical stuff, either. That DIY mentality applies to everything in my life … doing taxes, starting businesses, writing websites/software, &amp;amp; designing logos. I really try to tackle all of these things myself.
 However, as of lately, I&amp;#8217;ve been feeling stretched really thin; too thin, actually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autorecover Sql Scripts</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/autorecover-sql-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/autorecover-sql-scripts/</guid>
      <description>This morning, when I came into work, I discovered that Windows Update had graciously restarted my machine for me. No big deal. But wait, then I realized I had some SQL work that I hadn&amp;#8217;t saved yet. NOOOOOO!!! I know, I know, &amp;#8230;&amp;#8203; always save your work. But yesterday, I didn&amp;#8217;t. So you can imagine how irritated I was to discover that all of that hard work was gone. Or so I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Ebook: Defensive Database Programming</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-defensive-database-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-defensive-database-programming/</guid>
      <description>Simple-Talk Publishing has released a new free eBook: Defensive Database Programming with SQL Server, by Alex Kuznetsov.
 The goal of Defensive Programming is to produce resilient code that responds gracefully to the unexpected. To the SQL Server programmer, this means T-SQL code that behaves consistently and predictably in cases of unexpected usage, doesn&amp;#8217;t break under concurrent loads, and survives predictable changes to database schemas and settings.
 Too often as developers, we stop work as soon as our code passes a few basic tests to confirm that it produces the &#39;right result&#39; in a given use case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passed My First Microsoft Certification Exam</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/passed-my-first-microsoft-certification-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/passed-my-first-microsoft-certification-exam/</guid>
      <description>Today, I passed my first Microsoft Certification exam, MCTS exam 70-433! With this certification, I am a Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist for SQL Server 2008 Database Development.
 Getting a MS cert has always been something that I always wanted to achieve, but I never thought I would have the time to study. Well I signed up back in April and just knew that if I didn’t just do it, I probably never would.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Book Of Red Gate</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/the-book-of-red-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/the-book-of-red-gate/</guid>
      <description>I’m a pretty big fan of RedGate. I use a few of their products almost religiously. Their SQL Compare product is probably the most used tool in my toolbox. I follow their blogs &amp;amp; evangelists, regularly consume their free eBooks, and generally admire the company as a whole. Their “Ingeniously Simple” mantra is really what keeps me coming back. I even started to apply for a job there once. However, the small requirement to live in England killed it for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Ebook: Introducing Microsoft Sql Server 2008 r2</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-introducing-microsoft-sql-server-2008-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-introducing-microsoft-sql-server-2008-r2/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Press has released a free ebook: Introducing Microsoft SQL Server R2, by Ross Mistry and Stacia Misner. There are 10 chapters and 216 pages. Here is a quick overview of the chapters:
 Chapter 1: SQL Server 2008 R2 Editions and Enhancements Chapter 2: Multi-Server Administration Chapter 3: Data-Tier Applications Chapter 4: High Availability and Virtualization Enhancements Chapter 5: Consolidation and Monitoring Chapter 6: Scalable Data Warehousing Chapter 7: Master Data Services Chapter 8: Complex Event Processing with StreamInsight Chapter 9: Reporting Services Enhancements Chapter 10: Self-Service Analysis with PowerPivot</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Feedburner Now</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/using-feedburner-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/using-feedburner-now/</guid>
      <description>I have moved my syndication feed over to feedburner. For those of you that are subscribers, please update the links in your readers. My new feed is http://feeds.feedburner.com/AdamHutson. I will be rolling out a new website in the near future and the old feed will no longer be active. I&amp;#8217;ll send out a last post as a reminder when it&amp;#8217;s officially closed. Thanks for understanding.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Microsoft Certification Exam</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/first-microsoft-certification-exam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/first-microsoft-certification-exam/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve signed up to take my first Microsoft Certification exam. I will be taking the MCTS Exam 70-433: SQL Server 2008 Database Development exam. The date is scheduled for May 26th with 3 hours allotted. I&amp;#8217;m hoping that it&amp;#8217;ll be a breeze, since I&amp;#8217;ve been writing TSQL for so long, but I&amp;#8217;m still nervous. I&amp;#8217;ve been reading the Training Kit on it and it&amp;#8217;s a really quick read. Wish me luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seconds Into DDHHMMSS Format</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/seconds-into-ddhhmmss-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/seconds-into-ddhhmmss-format/</guid>
      <description>Got a fun requirement today. Using SQL, the developer needed to convert an integer representing seconds into the format of dd:hh:mm:ss. So 125 seconds would be 00:00:02:05.
 I put together a quick script that creates a table variable, inserts some test values, and selects back out of it.
 DECLARE @ADAM TABLE(sec INT NULL) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (125) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (3600) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (3605) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (60000) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (6000) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (600) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (86400) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (86405) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (172800) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (172860) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (172865) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (1234567) INSERT INTO @ADAM (sec) VALUES (75654) SELECT RIGHT(&#39;0&#39; + CONVERT(varchar(6), sec/86400),2) + &#39;:&#39; + RIGHT(&#39;0&#39; + CONVERT(varchar(6), sec % 86400 / 3600), 2) + &#39;:&#39; + RIGHT(&#39;0&#39; + CONVERT(varchar(2), (sec % 3600) / 60), 2) + &#39;:&#39; + RIGHT(&#39;0&#39; + CONVERT(varchar(2), sec % 60), 2) FROM @ADAM   Results 00:00:02:05 00:01:00:00 00:01:00:05 00:16:40:00 00:01:40:00 00:00:10:00 01:00:00:00 01:00:00:05 02:00:00:00 02:00:01:00 02:00:01:05 14:06:56:07 00:21:00:54   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Ebook: How To Become An Exceptional DBA</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-how-to-become-an-exceptional-dba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-how-to-become-an-exceptional-dba/</guid>
      <description>Brad McGehee is one of my more favorite authors of SQL literature. How to Become an Exceptional DBA is one of his more popular books. It’s really a career guide for novice and experienced DBAs, alike. It shows step-by-step methods for how to differentiate yourself from the crowd. Most of it is common sense, but it’s a good reminder for how to be an exceptional DBA.
 You can download a free pdf version of this eBook here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Ebook: Don&#39;t Just Roll The Dice</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-dont-just-roll-the-dice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-dont-just-roll-the-dice/</guid>
      <description>One of the blogs that I follow is the Business Of Software, by Neil Davidson. Neil is the co-founder and joint CEO of Red Gate Software and the organizer of the Business of Software conference. Back in October, Neil released a free eBook, Don’t Just Roll the Dice. It’s a useful, short book on how to price software. It includes theory, practical advice and case studies so that software pricing isn’t a roll of the dice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Ebook: Getting Real</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-getting-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/free-ebook-getting-real/</guid>
      <description>37signals is one those companies that you just can’t help but notice. And once you do, you won’t be able to keep from following them and their philosophies. They are the guys that invented Ruby On Rails. They follow the strict mantra that software products should be built with the least number of features possible. Getting Real: The smarter, faster, easier way to build a successful web application is a new book written by the crew at 37signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money Vs Decimal Data Types In Sql Server</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/money-vs-decimal-data-types-in-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/money-vs-decimal-data-types-in-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>Last week, one of our developers asked us in the DBA group what our standard was for currency columns. My first thought was DECIMAL(19,4), but I couldn’t give a reason why it was standard. I knew MONEY was essentially the same definition, but had heard that it was dangerous to use. Suspecting a rounding issue, I began with a simple test.
 DECLARE @dOne DECIMAL(19,4), @dThree DECIMAL(19,4), @mOne MONEY, @mThree MONEY SELECT @dOne = 1, @dThree = 3, @mOne = 1, @mThree = 3 SELECT @dOne / @dThree * @dThree AS DecimalResult, @mOne / @mThree * @mThree AS MoneyResult   DecimalResult MoneyResult 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzle Solved</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/puzzle-solved/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/puzzle-solved/</guid>
      <description>I have been really getting into RSS feeds lately and have subscribed to alot of ones that interest me. I personally have been using the Google Reader on the iGoogle homepage. It&amp;#8217;s a neat way to keep tabs on my varied readings. One that caught my eye was a challenge by Pinal Dave. Pinal challenged his readers to solve a puzzle that would return the size of each index for a speficied table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nullability And Default Constraint Behavior</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/nullabitlity-and-default-constraint-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/nullabitlity-and-default-constraint-behavior/</guid>
      <description>When adding a new column with a default constraint to an existing table, keep in mind what you want your existing records to contain. If you add the new column and set it to be allow nulls, then all of the existing records will contain a NULL, and any inserted records will have the default value. However, if you set new column’s nullability to be NOT NULL, then the existing records will get back-filled with the default value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golfing With My Son In November</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/golfing-with-my-son-in-november/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/golfing-with-my-son-in-november/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, my 5-yr old son, Logan, and my step-father-in-law, Jerry, and I went to play golf &amp;#8230;&amp;#8203; in November! Being in the hign-60&amp;#8217;s, it was just TOO nice of a day to not take advantage of it. Logan really has a surprisingly good tee-shot. He made it on the green with one tee-shot and chipped one in from 15-ft away in the rough! Pretty stinking amazing for a kid that doesn&amp;#8217;t get to play too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing In The Leaves At The Nature Center</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/playing-in-the-leaves-at-the-nature-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/playing-in-the-leaves-at-the-nature-center/</guid>
      <description>Today, I got to go play in the fall leaves with my family out at the Nature Center. What a great day! We are still having awesome weather and the leaves are perfect right now. We even got to actually watch them fall from the trees. The kids ate it up! It was Suzanne&amp;#8217;s idea to go take them out. In the past years, we never needed to go somewhere to experience leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sql Server Memory Management</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/sql-server-memory-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/sql-server-memory-management/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had the opportunity to brush up on my SQL Server memory tuning skills. It&amp;#8217;s been a while since I needed them, but I thought I&amp;#8217;d throw out what I used for someone else&amp;#8217;s future benefit.
 First, some background knowledge: There are different physical memory limits for each Windows release. The virtual address space (set of virtual memory addresses) is limited to 4 GB for 32-bit Windows. The virtual address space is divided into two 2 GB partitions: one for use by the processes and other reserved for use by the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implicit Conversion Of Fast Forward Cursor To Static Cursor</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/implicit-conversion-of-fast-forward-cursor-to-static-cursor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/implicit-conversion-of-fast-forward-cursor-to-static-cursor/</guid>
      <description>During the course of one of my last blog posts on Cursors, I ran across a niche piece of information that I didn&amp;#8217;t realize. I had always read that FAST_FORWARD CURSORs were the fastest and least locking of the different CURSOR types. What I didn&amp;#8217;t realize was that if the SELECT statement joins on one or more tables with a trigger table (INSERTED/DELETED), the CURSOR is converted to a STATIC CURSOR!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding The Last Reboot Time Of A Sql Server</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/finding-the-last-reboot-time-of-a-sql-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/finding-the-last-reboot-time-of-a-sql-server/</guid>
      <description>Here is a quick way to find the last reboot date and time of a SQL Server instance.
 For SQL Server 2000 or 2005, use: SELECT crdate FROM master.dbo.sysdatabases WHERE name = &#39;tempdb&#39;
 For SQL Server 2008, use: SELECT sqlserver_start_time FROM master.sys.dm_os_sys_info
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoid Cursors, Rewrite Into While Loops</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/avoid-cursors-rewrite-into-while-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/avoid-cursors-rewrite-into-while-loops/</guid>
      <description>A few months back, we had a stored proc at work that was using CURSORs pretty heavily. It had CURSORs inside of CURSORs. This proc was one of our oldest, biggest, and most involved procs at over 2050 lines. On larger clients, it could be called thousands of times a day. All of the cursors were FAST_FORWARD types, which should have at least been somewhat performance friendly. However they were SELECTing from tables that had triggers which implicitly converted the cursor type to be STATIC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal: Explore More Solutions Than Just WinForms</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/goal-explore-more-solutions-than-just-winforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/goal-explore-more-solutions-than-just-winforms/</guid>
      <description>It seems to me lately that I am continually writing, essentially, the same program for every problem. The language has changed from VB6 to VB.NET to C#, but the pattern behind the design is the same. It&amp;#8217;s always a Winform front end, common logic/objects in a middle dll, and data access from another dll that usually hits stored procedures on a SQL Server. Not that it&amp;#8217;s a bad design, because it&amp;#8217;s not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free iPhone Development Training</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/free-iphone-development-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/free-iphone-development-training/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I was talking with a friend about programming on an iPhone. We were discussing the potential audience that an iPhone commanded. I didn&amp;#8217;t know much how the iPhone operated (I don&amp;#8217;t own one), however, it did pique my interest enough to research it a bit. So, shortly after that conversation, I went to the Apple Dev Center and perused the Getting Started Documentation. Well, it was more than a little confusing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Makes Up A Good Blog</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/what-makes-up-a-good-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/what-makes-up-a-good-blog/</guid>
      <description>In starting this blog, I have to ask, What amount and kind of content makes up good blog? My goal is for it to define me as a familyman, and professional. It should be about what interests me. That being technology, family, books, &amp;amp; thoughts. I believe that it should reflect the balance in life in which I do all of those things. For me, about 50% of my time is consumed by technology, 30% is enjoying family, and remaining 20% is split evenly between books &amp;amp; thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Branding</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/personal-branding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/personal-branding/</guid>
      <description>Personal branding is a new concept that I&amp;#8217;ve just recently discovered. The idea is that your professional and personal lives are interconnected. Meaning that what you do after work is just as important as what you do during work. This new blog is the first step of many to brand myself. I am really excited about this new self-packaging approach. Hopefully, it will give a better perspective of what goes on in my whole life, what drives me, what I&amp;#8217;m thinking about, and where I&amp;#8217;m going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/about/</guid>
      <description>all about moi
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>how to get ahold of me
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>places I&amp;#8217;ve worked and school I attended
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>http://adamhutson.com/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamhutson.com/talks/</guid>
      <description>all of the talks I&amp;#8217;ve given
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>